<channel>
<title>Catholic Online > Latest News</title>
<description>Read the latest news from Catholic Online.</description>
<link>https://www.catholic.org</link>
<copyright>Copyright 2024 Catholic Online</copyright>
<language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 07:49:06 PDT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Celebrate St. Francis of Assisi with the top 10 quotes from and for him </title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=71063</link>
<description>Today is St. Francis of Assisi's feast day!</description>
<author>Kenya Sinclair </author>
<pubDate>2024-10-04 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=71063</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From St Francis of Assisi to the Faithful: We Must be Simple</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/saints/story.php?id=52623</link>
<description>We must not be wise and prudent according to the flesh. Rather we must be simple, humble and pure. We should never desire to be over others. Instead, we ought to be servants who are submissive to every human being for God's sake. The Spirit of the Lord will rest on all who live in this way and persevere in it to the end. He will permanently dwell in them. They will be the Father's children who do his work. They are the spouses, brothers and mothers of our Lord Jesus Christ.</description>
<author>St. Francis of Assisi</author>
<pubDate>2024-10-04 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/saints/story.php?id=52623</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From Plows to Profit: The Rise of Industrialized Agriculture in America</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/green/story.php?id=87297</link>
<description>The industrialization of agriculture in America began in the early 20th century and was driven by a combination of technological advances, economic forces, and government policies. Prior to industrialization, farming in the U.S. was largely small-scale, labor-intensive, and diversified, with most farmers growing a variety of crops and raising livestock. However, this began to change with the advent of new machinery, synthetic fertilizers, and changes in agricultural policy.</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-10-03 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/green/story.php?id=87297</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nehemiah's Wall: A Testament to Faith, Leadership, and Restoration</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87295</link>
<description>The story of Nehemiah's Wall is one of determination, faith, leadership, and a community's commitment to restoring both its physical and spiritual foundation. Found in the Old Testament, the Book of Nehemiah recounts the extraordinary efforts of Nehemiah, a Jewish leader, who led the people of Jerusalem in rebuilding the city's walls after they had been left in ruin following the Babylonian exile. This reconstruction was not just a physical undertaking--it symbolized the renewal of the people's ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-10-03 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87295</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Adorable animals PRAY on St. Francis of Assisi's feast day (PHOTOS) </title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=71213</link>
<description>"If God can work through me, he can work through anyone."</description>
<author>Abigail James </author>
<pubDate>2024-10-03 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=71213</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What's Different About the Catholic Bible? A Catholic Perspective on the Canon of Scripture</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87293</link>
<description>One of the most significant differences between Catholicism and Protestantism is the canon of the Bible--the collection of books recognized as inspired by God and included in Scripture. Catholics and Protestants share a majority of the same biblical texts, but there are several key differences in the number of books included in the Old Testament. The Catholic Bible contains seven books that are not found in most Protestant Bibles, along with additional sections in two other books.</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-10-02 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87293</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Silent Killers: The Toxic Legacy of Petrochemicals on Our Health</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/health/story.php?id=87291</link>
<description>Over the past three generations, the widespread use of petrochemicals in agriculture, industry, and consumer products has had profound health consequences. The chemicals used in pesticides, fertilizers, plastics, and various industrial processes are increasingly linked to a rise in chronic diseases, including cancer, diabetes, heart disease, autism, and obesity. The sheer scale of their impact is alarming, and many experts believe that the prevalence of these diseases is a direct result of ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-10-02 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/health/story.php?id=87291</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Our Water is Poisoned: A Wake-Up Call for America</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/health/story.php?id=87289</link>
<description>A shocking study by the U.S. Geological Survey reveals that nearly half of the tap water in the United States is contaminated with toxic "forever chemicals," or PFAS (Per- and Polyfluoroalkyl Substances). These chemicals have infiltrated our water supply, and their presence poses grave health risks, including cancer, liver damage, immune system disorders, and hormone disruption. PFAS are used in everyday items like non-stick cookware and water-resistant fabrics, but their persistence in the ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-10-01 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/health/story.php?id=87289</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Disturbing Trend: 14 Church Fires in France Linked to Criminal Activity in 2023</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/international/europe/story.php?id=87285</link>
<description>In 2023, a troubling pattern of church fires has cast a shadow over France's religious landscape. According to a report by Le Figaro, 14 church fires have been linked to criminal activity this year alone, raising concerns about the safety of the country's Christian heritage and the increasing threat of violence against places of worship. These incidents, occurring against a backdrop of rising secularism, societal tension, and anti-religious sentiment, have left communities shaken and prompted a ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-10-01 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/international/europe/story.php?id=87285</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Sign of the Cross: A Powerful and Sacred Gesture in Catholic Tradition</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87283</link>
<description>The Sign of the Cross is one of the most fundamental and recognizable acts in Catholic worship and prayer. It is a simple yet deeply meaningful gesture that carries profound spiritual significance. From the moment Catholics enter a church, begin a prayer, or conclude a liturgical celebration, the Sign of the Cross is present. But why do Catholics make the Sign of the Cross, and what is its origin, meaning, and importance within the Church?</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-30 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87283</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Carmel Mission: A Hub of Agriculture and Faith in Early California</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/national/story.php?id=87281</link>
<description>The Carmel Mission, also known as Mission San Carlos Borromeo de Carmelo, played a crucial role in the spread of Christianity and European civilization in California during the late 18th and early 19th centuries. Established in 1770 by Fr. Junipero Serra, the mission served as his headquarters and became the heart of religious activity across California. Alongside its spiritual significance, Carmel Mission developed into a major center for agricultural and ranching operations, essential to the ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-30 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/national/story.php?id=87281</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ronald Reagan's Inauguration: A Legacy of Faith and Leadership Rooted in History</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/politics/story.php?id=87279</link>
<description>On January 3, 1967, Ronald Reagan stood before the people of California to take the oath of office as the 33rd Governor of the state. It was a moment of great political significance for Reagan, who was stepping into the spotlight as a new voice in American conservatism. But the historical weight of that moment was not only political--it was deeply spiritual. Reagan chose to take his oath of office with his hand resting on a Bible that had traveled across the deserts and mountains with Father ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-30 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/politics/story.php?id=87279</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What is an Archangel?</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=71087</link>
<description>What is an archangel? This is a common question. Simply put, an archangel is an angel of high rank. Three are mentioned in the Bible. Saint Michael, Saint Gabriel, and Saint Raphael.</description>
<author>Marshall Connolly (CALIFORNIA NETWORK)</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-29 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=71087</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Genesis 1:7-9: A Catholic Perspective on Creation and the Flat Earth Theory</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87277</link>
<description>The book of Genesis, as the first text in the Bible, lays the foundation for the Catholic understanding of God's creation of the world. In Genesis 1:7-9, we read about the division of the waters and the formation of dry land, a crucial moment in the creation narrative:</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-27 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87277</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Voltaire's Prophecy: The Triumph of the Bible in His Own Home</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87275</link>
<description>In the mid-18th century, French philosopher Voltaire was at the height of his influence, boldly challenging religious beliefs, particularly those of the Catholic Church, which he saw as a symbol of superstition and oppression.</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-27 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87275</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Promise to God: St. Michael the Archangel, Defend Us in Battle</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/saints/story.php?id=51793</link>
<description>Though I am not strong enough to hold the suffering souls in my arms and carry them home, I can do one thing: I can pray for the deliverance of the souls who are in the darkness. I can request help from the angels for them. I can make a 911 call for them. So again, I sat down this morning to pray the rosary, and to say a prayer to St. Michael. I was not surprised that many souls came to my mind. The Spirit kept adding more and more souls on my list of prayer, and I was only happy to oblige.</description>
<author>Youngsun Jun </author>
<pubDate>2024-09-27 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/saints/story.php?id=51793</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Hail Mary: One of the Catholic Church's Most Powerful Prayers</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87273</link>
<description>The Hail Mary is one of the most beloved and powerful prayers in the Catholic Church, echoing through the centuries as a prayer of devotion, intercession, and faith. It is a prayer that captures both the reverence Catholics hold for the Blessed Virgin Mary and the Church's deep-rooted belief in the power of her intercession. This simple yet profound prayer holds a special place in Catholic devotion, reflecting the central mysteries of the Incarnation and the role of Mary as the Mother of God.</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-26 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87273</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ancient Tree with Biblical Significance Revived from 1,000-Year-Old Seed in Jerusalem</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/green/story.php?id=87271</link>
<description>In a remarkable discovery, scientists have revived a long-lost species of tree from a 1,000-year-old seed found in a cave near Jerusalem. This tree, named "Sheba," belongs to the frankincense and myrrh family, revered in the Bible for their spiritual and medicinal importance. Researchers believe it could be the tree that produced the biblical "tsori," a healing balm referenced in Genesis, Jeremiah, and Ezekiel. This resurrection holds significant implications for both scientific and religious ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-26 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/green/story.php?id=87271</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Timeless Power of the Latin Mass: A Wellspring of the World's Greatest Music</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87269</link>
<description>Throughout centuries of history, no religious ritual or act of worship has left a greater mark on the world's greatest music than the ancient Latin Mass of the Catholic Church. The Latin Mass, or Missa Latina, stands at the intersection of faith, art, and human expression, inspiring some of the most extraordinary compositions in Western music. From the soaring works of Renaissance polyphony to the grandeur of classical symphonies, the Latin Mass has been the muse for composers seeking to ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-25 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87269</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Century of Faith: The Astonishing Growth of Christianity in Sub-Saharan Africa</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/international/africa/story.php?id=87267</link>
<description>A hundred years ago, the vast expanse of sub-Saharan Africa echoed with the rhythms of ancestral traditions, where fewer than 2 million souls followed the teachings of Christ. Today, that number has swelled beyond 130 million. This transformation is more than a statistic; it is a testament to a profound spiritual awakening, one that has reshaped not only the faith of millions but the very fabric of African society.</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-25 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/international/africa/story.php?id=87267</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What's Wrong with Casual Sex? Everything, According to T.S. Eliot</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/health/story.php?id=87265</link>
<description>T.S. Eliot, one of the most influential poets and essayists of the 20th century, wasn't just known for his literary brilliance--he was also a sharp cultural critic who had much to say about the moral decline he witnessed in society. One of the key issues he warned against was casual sex, which he believed carried profound consequences for individuals, families, and society as a whole. Eliot's reflections on the dangers of casual intimacy remain strikingly relevant today, as they touch on themes ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-24 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/health/story.php?id=87265</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lebanon's Lost Identity: The Impact of Immigration and Hezbollah's Occupation on a Once Thriving Nation</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/international/middle_east/story.php?id=87263</link>
<description>Until the early 1970s, Lebanon was celebrated as "the Switzerland of the Middle East," a haven of peace, prosperity, and religious harmony. This small Mediterranean nation, with its stunning mountains and vibrant cultural life, was a beacon of hope in an often troubled region. Its Christian-majority population helped shape Lebanon into a thriving, cosmopolitan state, a financial hub with a unique blend of Eastern and Western influences. However, this era of stability and prosperity began to ...</description>
<author>Michael Galloway</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-24 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/international/middle_east/story.php?id=87263</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Padre Pio overcame suffering with hope, says Italian journalist </title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/international/europe/story.php?id=83019</link>
<description>More than 50 years after the death of Padre Pio, one of the last journalists to interview the saint has reflected on the saint's hope and suffering.</description>
<author>CNA News</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-23 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/international/europe/story.php?id=83019</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The modern-day miracles of Padre Pio </title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=70991</link>
<description>Known around the globe as simply "Padre Pio," Saint Pio of Pietrelcina has been called one of the "most active" saints in the Church, and continues to work miracles for those who pray through his intercession.</description>
<author>Elise Harris (CNA/EWTN News)</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-23 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=70991</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bringing Faith to the Big Screen: Brenda Lorena Garcia's Mission in Hollywood</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/ae/movies/story.php?id=87261</link>
<description>Brenda Lorena Garcia, the daughter of Salvadoran parents, was born and raised in Los Angeles, California. Though she grew up in a Catholic household, her relationship with God deepened through her experiences of suffering and healing. Now, as a voice actress and stunt double, she actively brings her faith into the Hollywood film industry. In a recent interview with Aleteia, Brenda shared her journey of faith and how she serves God both in her work and personal life.</description>
<author>Catholic Online</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-20 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/ae/movies/story.php?id=87261</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Vatican's Stance on Medjugorje</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87259</link>
<description>In a long-anticipated report, the Vatican has issued a nuanced stance on the decades-long alleged apparitions of the Blessed Virgin Mary in Medjugorje, Bosnia and Herzegovina. The Dicastery for the Doctrine of the Faith (DDF), in a Sept. 19, 2024 note signed by Cardinal Victor Manuel Fernandez and approved by Pope Francis, endorsed "prudent devotion" to the popular pilgrimage site but refrained from confirming the supernatural nature of the visions. This decision reflects both a recognition of ...</description>
<author>Catholic Online</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-19 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87259</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>America's Agricultural Shift: How the U.S. Is Becoming a Net Food Importer</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/national/story.php?id=87257</link>
<description>The United States, long known as one of the world's agricultural powerhouses, is now facing a significant shift in its food production and trade dynamics. For the third time in five years, the U.S. is poised to become a net food importer, meaning it will import more food than it exports. This marks a dramatic shift for a country that has traditionally enjoyed an agricultural trade surplus, exporting more food than it brings in.</description>
<author>Catholic Online</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-19 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/national/story.php?id=87257</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pope Francis Encourages Youth to Follow Blessed Carlo Acutis' Devotion to the Eucharist</title>
<link>https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87255</link>
<description>In a message released ahead of diocesan World Youth Day, Pope Francis invited young people to look to Blessed Carlo Acutis as a model for prioritizing the Eucharist, calling it "the great gift of the Eucharist." The Holy Father emphasized how the real presence of Christ in the Eucharist is a source of strength and hope for the faithful, particularly in today's challenging world.</description>
<author>Catholic Online</author>
<pubDate>2024-09-18 00:00:00</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.catholic.org/news/hf/faith/story.php?id=87255</guid>
</item>
</channel>
